Boryana Kremakova

Currently completing my 3rd year of my bachelor's degree in Web & Mobile Development. I am actively searching for summer internship opportunities in Glasgow to extend my knowledge and gain experience in the industry.

b.kremakova@gmail.com boryanakremakova.me linkedin.com/in/boryanakre makova/ https://github.com/bkrem60 0

EXPERIENCE

Lenovo Technologies UK, Renfrew — Student Work Placement

February 2020 - March 2020

- Learn about the business operations of different departments each week, such as project management, quality and service, accounting, supply chain as well as sales
- Increase customer satisfaction by helping out with day-to-day tasks

River Advice AG/River Catering Ltd, Cologne - Receptionist

January 2018 - March 2018

- Greet, register and assign rooms
- Verify credit and establish how the customer will pay for accommodation
- Contact housekeeping or maintenance staff to report any problems
- Issue room keys
- Issue invoices to external companies for food and accommodation
- Calculate monthly food inventory
- Answer telephones and provide callers with information, take messages or transfer calls to the appropriate individuals

TTEC Eastern Europe EAD, Bulgaria – Document Processing Specialist

Apr 2016 - Nov 2016

- Search electronic sources, such as databases or repositories, or manual sources for information
- Identify and classify documents or other electronic content according to characteristics such as security level, function, and metadata
- Approve or reject documents based on regulations
- Inform customer about reasons for rejections by email or phone

${\bf Brussels\ Booking\ Desk},\ {\bf Brussels\ -\it Trainee\ Accommodation\ Consultant}$

September 2014 - February 2015

- Improve the company's official website
- Organize accommodation for groups visiting Brussels during events and conferences

EDUCATION

Web & Mobile Development BSc (Hons), University of the West of Scotland

September 2018 - present

SKILLS

- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Java
- Python
- SQL
- C#
- Cisco

QUALIFICATIONS

Web Design with HTML & CSS

Achieved by completing a summer course on web design

CCNA Routing and Switching: Introduction to Networks

Achieved by completing an online test and practical assignment on Cisco Networking Academy

Online course - no certificate

Completed an online course on Transact-SQL Programming Techniques

- Communicate with potential and existing clients as well as partners by email or phone
- Handle requests for proposals, answering to the needs and demands of the customer
- Operate a telephone switchboard to answer, screen or forward calls, providing information, taking messages or scheduling appointments

NH Amsterdam Zuid, Amsterdam — *Trainee Housekeeping Supervisor*

September 2012 - February 2013

- Train room attendants
- Advise managers, receptionists or admittance personnel of rooms ready for occupancy
- Plan and prepare employees' work schedules
- Coordinate activities with other departments to ensure that services are provided in an efficient and timely manner
- Inspect work performed to ensure that it meets specifications and established standards
- Perform or assist with cleaning duties as necessary
- Establish and implement operational standards and procedures for the departments supervised
- Investigate complaints about service and equipment and take corrective action
- Achieved grade 8 out of 10 on hospitality performance

PROJECTS

Spaced Invaders Game App – *Under construction*

A game app being developed with object-oriented programming in Android Studio using Java and Visual Studio using C#.

IKEA Database – Group 3rd year University Project

Reverse engineer IKEA online business into a database. The project included physical and logical database design: EER modeling, relational schemas, data dictionary, scripts SQL queries, indexes, and views.

Film industry themed website — Individual 1st year University Project

A responsive website about the Lord of the Rings trilogy created on WebStorm using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Inventory GUI program – Joint 1st year University Project

This is an inventory system for an engineering company that manufactures aircraft components written in Python programming language. It has integrated GUI to make the program more user-friendly. The user can create batches with selected components, view details of batches and components, allocate stock to two locations of choice, search by product details such as unique manufacturers' batch number and individual component serial number as well as finish a component choosing between two types of finish. The program catches invalid input by the user and outputs relevant messages. It stores all batches and components in a json file.

Program to maintain projects – Joint 2nd year University Project

This project implements a dynamic structure to maintain details of current projects for an IT company. It is written in Java programming language and is divided into three steps. The first step implements a linked list that maintains projects. The user can add, find, display and remove projects. The second step implements an array list that maintains team members. The user can add, find, display and remove team members from projects. The final step combines both previous steps into a binary search tree.

Stream database – *Group 2nd year University Project*

Database design for a streaming company created in Microsoft SQL Management Studio. This project awakened my interest in database design and administration. I learned about ER modeling, relational schemas and data dictionaries. I also wrote SQL queries which introduced me to SQL and prompted me to take a summer online course on T-SQL Programming Techniques.

Business website – *Personal*

Created a responsive website about trays and shoulder blades for a construction machines sales and repairs company. It was created in Adobe Muse.

More information about some of my projects can be found on my portfolio website and GitHub account.